Hari Kiran Yalavarthi

Ph: 404-993-8536 | Email: harikiranyalavarthi9@gmail.com

Summary

Passionate Software Engineer/Consultant with more than 5 years of professional services experience in scoping requirements, managing projects, delivering strategy, and developing web applications, tools, and workflows for customers using JavaScript ES6+, React.js, Node.js, Express, REST APIs, PostgreSQL, and MongoDB.

Work Experience

Lead Software Engineer/Consultant, Tricentis - Atlanta, GA

Feb 2018 to present

- Lead and facilitated discovery conversations on Tricentis qTest migration and integration engagements.
- Lead qTest migration initiative in the company and generated more than \$1M ARR through consulting services.
- Provided strategy and guidance as the SME on qTest services to our customers, peers, and other business units.
- Designed and developed tools to migrate data from customer previous test management tools to qTest Manager.
- Created Agile & DevOps workflows for continuous testing using CI/CD, testing tools, and qTest Pulse/Launch.
- Developed features of qTest Scenario for Jira product using Pug.js, Node.js, Express, and MongoDB.

Software Engineer Intern, KMS Technology, Inc. - Atlanta, GA

Jun 2017 to Jan 2018

- Developed front-end modules of the Kobiton product using HTML5, CSS3, ES6, Reactstrap, React.js, and REST APIs.
- Wrote automation scripts using Java, Appium, Kobiton to test native, hybrid and mobile-web applications.
- Assisted in data migration testing to validate successful migration from HP QC/ALM to qTest Manager.

Graduate Research Assistant, Georgia State University - Atlanta, GA

Aug 2016 to May 2017

- Worked on a Data Visualization project with Professor Dr. Ying Zhu, funded by Creative Media Industries Institute.
- Created interactive and dynamic data visualizations on Cricket game statistics using ES6, React.js, and D3.js.
- Performed web scraping on a popular cricket website (ESPNcricinfo) using Cheerio, jQuery, Node.js, Express, and MongoDB to extract real-time data for visualizations.
- Worked as a lab instructor and grader for Java and Web development courses.

Software Developer Intern, Navtech - Hyderabad, India

Jan 2016 to Jun 2016

- Developed a web application for a restaurant client in a team of three developers using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and Angular 1.x.
- Designed and Developed RESTful APIs for communication using Node.js, Express, Mongoose, and MongoDB.
- Integrated sessions, token-based, OAuth authentication into the web application using Passport, JWT, and Express.

Education

Campbellsville University - Louisville, KY

Jan 2021 to Dec 2022

Master of Science in Information Technology Management

Georgia State University - Atlanta, GA

Aug 2016 to Dec 2017

Master of Science in Computer Science

Osmania University - Hyderabad, India

Oct 2012 to June 2016

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science

Skills

Programming & Server-side Languages: C, Java, Python, JavaScript ES6+, Node.js **Frameworks & Libraries:** React.js, Angular 1.x, Express.js, Pug.js, D3.js, Loopback

Web: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX, SASS, Webpack

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Oracle

Other: Git, Jira, Confluence, qTest, HP QC/ALM, ADO, Linux, Bash, Jenkins, Appium, JMeter, Wireshark